Glorious Satria

Bandung, West Java, Indonesia

glorioussatria@gmail.com

082241389340

linkedin.com/in/gloriousatria

Summary

Hi.

My name is Glorious Satria.

While pursuing a Software Engineering degree at Telkom University, I am developing the Software Engineering paradigms and way of thinking that helps me strive in this adaptive industry. Despite being a strict Software Engineer, I always try to seek and find new opportunities that both can help me pursue my goals and help you to achieve your goals as well. I have worked on several projects that involved utilizing various technologies but not limited, such as:

- PHP (Laravel)
- C# (.NET & ASP.NET)
- JavaScript (ExpressJS)
- SQL (MySQL & PostgreSQL)
- NoSQL (Firebase & MongoDB)
- Caching (Redis)

My particular interest lies in developing secure, fast, maintainable, scalable, and adaptable systems, and I believe my technical expertise and experience make me a suitable candidate for an internship, full-time or part-time position.

Furthermore, I possess excellent communication skills and thrive in team-oriented environments, always willing to collaborate and provide assistance. I am enthusiastic and self-motivated, continuously seeking to acquire new knowledge and skills.

Check my repositories for further and detailed information: https://github.com/satriadhm

Experience

Software Quality Assurance Engineer

Dinotis Official

Sep 2023 - Present (5 months)

Assigned to Android Division.

- Performed manual testing to Dinotis android product.
- Delivered defect reports to development team.
- Implemented Black-Box Testing method for the product's functionalities testing.
- · Conducted research in terms of increasing Dinotis' product, process, and project quality.

Fracticum Assistant

Informatics Laboratory Telkom University

Sep 2022 - Present (1 year 5 months)

Assigned to Object Oriented Programming practicum.

- Provided guidance to 30+ practicum students in the Object-Oriented practicum course. | Java, MySQL
- Performed regular data entry tasks on student project grades.

Assigned to Programming Algorithm practicum

- Provided guidance to 30+ practicum students in the Programming Algorithm practicum course. | Go-
- Performed regular data entry tasks on student project grades.



Software Engineer - Server

FPT Software

Aug 2023 - Sep 2023 (2 months)

As a Software Engineer intern on the server-side, I managed server infrastructure and ensured the smooth operation of "MyFPT," an employee management product for FPT.

Responsibilities:

- Developed the PEAR service, integrating employee tasks across FPT internal websites, improving productivity. | NodeJS, ExpressJS
- Implemented a Service-Oriented Architecture (Controller-Service-Repository) for the PEAR service's API. | ExpressJS
- Set up Continuous Integration using Docker and Gitlab-Runner for the PEAR service's development. Docker, Gitlab-Runner
- Designed a custom AES Encryption Algorithm for the Authentication sub-system in PEAR service. NodeJS, ExpressJS
- Implemented a retry mechanism for the Redis Message Queue Instance. | Redis, RDMQ, ExpressJS, **NodeJS**
- Conducted API, Performance, and Load Testing on the authentication service using JMeter and Postman. | JMeter, Postman

Junior Software Engineer - Web

Kamar Pelajar

Jun 2023 - Jul 2023 (2 months)

I worked as a Software Engineer on the server-side primarily using Laravel and MySQL. My responsibilities included:

- Developed the "Pemandu" service, connecting users with local guides to enhance travel experiences. This service covered a wide range of travel activities. (PHP-Laravel, MySQL)
- Created the "Pesan" service, a user-friendly communication platform within the KamarPelajar network, facilitating interactions and meaningful connections. (PHP-Laravel, MySQL)
- · Contributed to improving KamarPelajar's database infrastructure through Laravel database migration, optimizing the database schema for better data management and system performance. (PHP-Laravel, MySQL)

I worked with the IT-Pandu team from July 2023 and the IT-Research team from March to July 2023.

Laboratory Assistant

Advanced Software Engineering Laboratory

Jan 2023 - Jul 2023 (7 months)

- Co-Lead the recruitment phase to new laboratory intern members.
- Assisted new intern members in understanding some of Software Engineering topics.

Conducted 4 weeks pra-intern meeting to the new member in recruitment phase.



Lecture Assistant

Telkom University

Oct 2022 - Jul 2023 (10 months)

Assigned to Programming Algorithm Course

- Provided guidance to 40+ students on programming algorithms. | GO-Lang
- Part-timed as an assistant from February 2023.
- Performed grading to freshman projects. | GO-Lang

Assigned to Software Process Course

- Provide guidance to 40+ students on Introduction to Software Process. | SCRUM, V-Model, Waterfall, RAD.
- Part-timed as an assistant from February 2023

Assigned to Software Requirement Engineering Course

- Provide guidance to 40+ students on Software Requirement Gathering and Analysis phase.
- Part-timed as an assistant from February 2023

Assigned to Software Modelling Course

- Provide guidance to 40+ students on Software Modelling using Unified Modelling Language. | UML -AstahUML.
- Part-timed as an assistant from February 2023

Assigned to Introduction to Programming Course

- Provide guidance to 100+ students on programming introduction. | GO-Lang
- Part-timed as an assistant from October 2022

Assigned to Introduction to Software Engineering Course

- Provide feedback and guidance to 40+ students on Introduction to Software Engineering projects.
- Conducted research and development on the introduction to software engineering topics directed by the lecturer to improvise learning techniques
- Part-timed as an assistant from October 2022.

Assigned to Design Thinking Course

- Provide feedback and guidance to 40+ students on Introduction to Design Thinking projects. | Figma
- Part-timed as an assistant from October 2022.

Software Engineer - Web

Kamar Pelajar

Mar 2023 - Jun 2023 (4 months)

As a Software Engineer in server-side, I mainly worked in Laravel server and MySQL Database. I ensured that all functionality worked well and met the defined requirements.

Assigned to IT-Research team.

• Developed "Penghuni" services. "Penghuni" services serve as a management service to help KamarPelajar Employee to manage their works and account. | PHP-Laravel, MySQL

- · Contributed to develop "Pemandu" services. Pemandu is designed to facilitate seamless travel experiences for users within destination areas. The "Pemandu" service operates by connecting users with experienced local guides, referred to as "Pemandus," who serve as native experts and assist users in various aspects of their travel activities. These activities encompass a wide range of services and support, making "Pemandu" an invaluable resource for travelers seeking a deeper and more authentic exploration of their chosen destinations. | PHP-Laravel, MySQL
- Enhanced KamarPelajar.id documentation | figma, Trello

Project Management

Mobile Innovation Laboratory

Mar 2023 - May 2023 (3 months)

- Assigned as a Product Management member.
- Joined a bootcamp from dinotis.com named LEAD Bootcamp.
- Refined dinotis.com mobile product in fixed-length weeks through LEAD Bootcamp.
- Built a new solution to dinotis.com mobile product to help them solving problems defined.

Peer Tutor

KONTENT HIMA IF Telkom University

Nov 2022 - Mar 2023 (5 months)

- Provided assistance and guidance about programming in GO-language to Informatics freshmen.
- Delivered an understanding of the fundamental of programming.
- · Delivered algorithm lecture courses and accompanied Informatics freshmen in their ways to understand the topic.

S Back End Engineer Specialist

Sagara Technology

Dec 2022 - Feb 2023 (3 months)

- Developed user-buyer and user-seller services. | Python-Django
- Defined the backlogs with Project Manager.
- · Learned about Django Framework.

Digital Business / Project Management Intern

Mobile Innovation Laboratory

Nov 2022 - Feb 2023 (4 months)

- Learned about Software Development Life Cycle
- Learned about Project Management using OKR framework (Objective-Key Result).
- Learned about Digital Business Frameworks.
- Conducted research about an innovation based on Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs).
- Created such documents as PRD and Business Plan according to the innovation founded.
- · Created test case document as a Quality Assurance phase to make sure the development phase is consistent with the requirement that defined before.

Education



Telkom University

Bachelor of Engineering - BE, Computer Software Engineering



Licenses & Certifications

- Certified English Proficiency EF Standard English Test (EF SET)
- English Communicative Competence Test Telkom University Issued Dec 2021 Expires Dec 2023
- Technical Support Fundamentals Coursera
- Administration System and IT Infrastructure Services Coursera L3LYSABNP6A7
- NodeJS: Advanced Concepts Udemy UC-9c691f2b-e920-4f2d-87c8-37d0602ffaa8
- TVRI Anniversary | Planting 1000 Cisanti Trees TVRI Nasional

Skills

Collaborative Problem Solving • Engineering • Research • SQL • Laravel • Databases • Communication • Easily Adaptable • Project Management • Problem Solving

Honors & Awards

2nd Winner on UX Competition FIND IT! 2023 DTETI Universitas Gadjah Mada -

Department of Electrical and Information Engineering, Gadjah Mada University Jun 2023

The UX Competition is a competition for designing the user experience (UX) of a mobile application, which is one of the branches of the Find IT! 2023 competition. This competition combines several aspects of startups, including achieving user experience goals and usability goals. The theme of the UX Competition this time is "Towards a Resilient Tomorrow: Harnessing the Power of Digital Transformation to Address Today's Challenges".

1st Winner on MotionHack 2.0 x Dinotis - Mobile Innovation Laboratory Telkom University x Dinotis

Feb 2023

MotionHack is a competition held by Mobile Innovation Laboratory Telkom University in order to accomplish the intern phase. In this competition, I become a Project Manager supervising 2 UI/UX designers and 1 Mobile Programmer to refine the Dinotis android app.

Top 10 Al For Accessibility Microsoft Hackathon - Microsoft Indonesia and Faculty of Informatics Telkom University

Jun 2023

An incredible journey where our team developed Microsoft extension dedicated to empowering individuals with disabilities. Our innovation aimed to enhance accessibility, making technology inclusive for all. We got the chance to present our idea before Microsoft executives and representatives from disability organizations, showcasing our commitment to creating positive impact through technology. Grateful for the opportunity to contribute to a more inclusive future.